<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Observability on Vincent Behar</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/tags/observability/</link><description>Recent content in Observability on Vincent Behar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vincent.behar.name/tags/observability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Jenkins X is Integrating Observability from the Inside, and the Benefits for its Users</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-06-cdcon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-06-cdcon/</guid><description>At the cdCon conference, in june 2021, I gave a talk titled How Jenkins X is Integrating Observability from the Inside, and the Benefits for its Users.
In this talk, I explained what observability means for a Continuous Delivery platform such as Jenkins X, and why it&amp;rsquo;s important.
I went through how Jenkins X v3 is integrating observability from the inside, using standards such as OpenTelemetry, and packaging a full observability stack using Grafana - with Loki, Promtail, Tempo, and Prometheus.</description></item><item><title>Using Grafana to visualize Continuous Delivery Indicators in the open source Jenkins X cloud native CI/CD project</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-06-grafanacon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-06-grafanacon/</guid><description>At the GrafanaCONline 2021 Conference, I gave a talk titled Using Grafana to visualize Continuous Delivery Indicators in the open source Jenkins X cloud native CI/CD project - yes, I&amp;rsquo;m competing for the longest conference talk title!
In this talk, I shared how we are using Grafana in Jenkins X for everything observability-related, and more specifically to visualize Continuous Delivery Indicators:
why Grafana how Grafana is setup in a Kubernetes cluster how the CD indicators application is exposing its dashboards and datasource for Grafana to consume You can watch the talk on the Grafana website.</description></item><item><title>Jenkins X Observability with Grafana Demo</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-03-jx-office-hours/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-03-jx-office-hours/</guid><description>At the Jenkins X Office Hours, in march 2021, I did another demo of using the Grafana stack (loki/promtail, tempo, prometheus and grafana) for platform-level and Continuous Delivery Indicators observability in a Jenkins X platform (tekton, lighthouse, &amp;hellip;)
Tomorrow at the @jenkinsxio Office Hours I&amp;#39;ll do another demo and status update on the @grafana integration. Observability is coming to Jenkins X!
&amp;mdash; Vincent Behar (@vbehar) March 22, 2021</description></item><item><title>Jenkins X Observability with Grafana Demo</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-02-jx-office-hours/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-02-jx-office-hours/</guid><description>At the Jenkins X Office Hours, in february 2021, I did a demo of how to setup the Grafana stack (loki/promtail, tempo, prometheus and grafana) in a Jenkins X platform (tekton, lighthouse, &amp;hellip;)
If you&amp;#39;re into CI/CD and observability, tomorrow at the @jenkinsxio Office Hours I&amp;#39;ll do a demo of how to setup the @grafana stack (loki, promtail, tempo, prometheus and grafana) in a Jenkins X platform (tekton, lighthouse, .</description></item><item><title>Collecting and visualizing Continuous Delivery Indicators</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-02-fosdem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-02-fosdem/</guid><description>At the Fosdem 2021 Conference, I gave a talk titled Collecting and visualizing Continuous Delivery Indicators in a Kubernetes-based CI/CD platform, using Jenkins X, Lighthouse, Tekton, PostgreSQL and Grafana in the CI/CD devroom.
In this talk, I shared our experience at Dailymotion on:
defining CD Indicators collecting them from a Kubernetes-based CI/CD platform storing them in PostgreSQL visualizing them using Grafana You can watch the talk on video.fosdem.org or directly here:</description></item></channel></rss>