<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open Source Contributions on Vincent Behar</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/</link><description>Recent content in Open Source Contributions on Vincent Behar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jenkins X</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/jenkins-x/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/jenkins-x/</guid><description>Jenkins X is a CI/CD platform on top of Kubernetes. I started using it while it was still a young project, in september 2018.
I made various contributions:
code, of course - including bug fixes and new features documentation and blog posts on the Jenkins X blog support on the community Slack channels demos at Office Hours - see recordings on YouTube talks at conferences and meetups, and interviews on podcasts &amp;hellip; I also got a few awards, such as:</description></item><item><title>Helm Ecosystem</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/helm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/helm/</guid><description>Helm is a package manager for Kubernetes. It is the tool most people use to package their applications, and then deploy on Kubernetes. It is also the core of an ecosystem growing every day: plugins, wrapper tools, charts, &amp;hellip;
I have been contributing to a few open-source projects in the Helm ecosystem:
Helmfile - a &amp;ldquo;declarative spec for deploying helm charts&amp;rdquo; Helm Unit Tests plugin - a plugin for running unit tests on Helm charts Helm Tiller plugin - a plugin for running Helm in &amp;ldquo;tiller-less&amp;rdquo; mode in Helm 2 Helm charts - various contributions to common charts I&amp;rsquo;ve been using</description></item><item><title>Osiris</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/osiris/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/osiris/</guid><description>Osiris is &amp;ldquo;a general purpose, scale-to-zero component for Kubernetes&amp;rdquo;. As explained in the Zero cost preview environments on Kubernetes with Jenkins X and Osiris blog post I wrote, Osiris is an excellent tool to keep a Jenkins X cluster size under control.
I contributed multiple new features and bug fixes to Osiris.
As the original project has now been archived, I&amp;rsquo;m maintaining a fork on the Dailymotion OSS organization - as well as how to use it in Jenkins X.</description></item><item><title>Kaniko</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/kaniko/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/kaniko/</guid><description>Kaniko is &amp;ldquo;a tool to build container images from a Dockerfile, inside a container or Kubernetes cluster&amp;rdquo;.
In 2018 when I started using Jenkins X to power our CI/CD pipelines on Kubernetes, I quickly identified Kaniko to build our container images.
Unfortunately, as explained in the Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s journey from Jenkins to Jenkins X blog post I wrote, I found a few bugs which I fixed in Kaniko:
Fix for multi-stage builds Fix to allow building multiple images using the same container I also added a few new features:</description></item><item><title>OpenShift</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/openshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/openshift/</guid><description>OpenShift is a Kubernetes &amp;ldquo;distribution&amp;rdquo; developed by Red Hat.
In the summer of 2015 I started using this newly announced platform, and as always when working with new projects, found a lot of opportunities for improvements.
This is how I contributed new features, bug fixes, bug reports and documentation in:
OpenShift Origin - including support for custom Dockerfile path when building Docker images OpenShift source-to-image - the tool used to build container images without using Dockerfiles OpenShift Documentation I also contributed to the OpenShift completion for oh-my-zsh plugin.</description></item><item><title>Elastic4s</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/elastic4s/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/elastic4s/</guid><description>Elastic4s is an Elasticsearch client for Scala.
In 2014, while working on a Scala-based CMS - Content Management System - with an integrated search engine based on Elasticsearch, I found myself using the Elastic4s open-source project. And as it often happens, not all our use-cases were covered by the existing features, so I contributed a few new features.
See all my contributions.
At some point I also became a committer on the project.</description></item><item><title>Rundeck</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/rundeck/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/projects/contributions/rundeck/</guid><description>Rundeck is an &amp;ldquo;open source automation service&amp;rdquo;. As explained in the Continuous Deployment with Jenkins and Rundeck talk I gave in 2011, Rundeck is an excellent tool to build a Continuous Deployment pipeline, on top of Jenkins.
I wrote a few contributions to Rundeck.</description></item></channel></rss>