<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conference on Vincent Behar</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/tags/conference/</link><description>Recent content in Conference on Vincent Behar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vincent.behar.name/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Jenkins X is Integrating Observability from the Inside, and the Benefits for its Users</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-06-cdcon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-06-cdcon/</guid><description>At the cdCon conference, in june 2021, I gave a talk titled How Jenkins X is Integrating Observability from the Inside, and the Benefits for its Users.
In this talk, I explained what observability means for a Continuous Delivery platform such as Jenkins X, and why it&amp;rsquo;s important.
I went through how Jenkins X v3 is integrating observability from the inside, using standards such as OpenTelemetry, and packaging a full observability stack using Grafana - with Loki, Promtail, Tempo, and Prometheus.</description></item><item><title>Using Grafana to visualize Continuous Delivery Indicators in the open source Jenkins X cloud native CI/CD project</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-06-grafanacon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-06-grafanacon/</guid><description>At the GrafanaCONline 2021 Conference, I gave a talk titled Using Grafana to visualize Continuous Delivery Indicators in the open source Jenkins X cloud native CI/CD project - yes, I&amp;rsquo;m competing for the longest conference talk title!
In this talk, I shared how we are using Grafana in Jenkins X for everything observability-related, and more specifically to visualize Continuous Delivery Indicators:
why Grafana how Grafana is setup in a Kubernetes cluster how the CD indicators application is exposing its dashboards and datasource for Grafana to consume You can watch the talk on the Grafana website.</description></item><item><title>Collecting and visualizing Continuous Delivery Indicators</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-02-fosdem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-02-fosdem/</guid><description>At the Fosdem 2021 Conference, I gave a talk titled Collecting and visualizing Continuous Delivery Indicators in a Kubernetes-based CI/CD platform, using Jenkins X, Lighthouse, Tekton, PostgreSQL and Grafana in the CI/CD devroom.
In this talk, I shared our experience at Dailymotion on:
defining CD Indicators collecting them from a Kubernetes-based CI/CD platform storing them in PostgreSQL visualizing them using Grafana You can watch the talk on video.fosdem.org or directly here:</description></item><item><title>Dailymotion's Continuous Delivery Story</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-10-cdcon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-10-cdcon/</guid><description>At the cdCon conference, in october 2020, I gave a talk titled Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s Continuous Delivery Story.
In this talk, I explained Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s initial CI/CD-related issues back in 2018, and how we solved them:
using practices from the Accelerate book using Jenkins X - a CD platform which implements the practices from the Accelerate book Register for #cdCON 2020 Virtual Oct. 7 &amp;amp; 8. @vbehar will share Dailymotion&amp;#39;s Continuous Delivery story with @jenkinsci, @jenkinsxio &amp;amp; @tektoncd.</description></item><item><title>Interview on the DevOps Radio Podcast</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-07-interview-devops-radio-podcast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-07-interview-devops-radio-podcast/</guid><description>At the DevOps World | Jenkins World 2019 Conference in Lisbon, I was interviewed by Brian Dawson from the DevOps Radio podcast.
We talked about:
me Dailymotion Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s ad-tech platform Continuous Delivery Jenkins X</description></item><item><title>1 year with Jenkins X</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-12-dwjw-lisbon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-12-dwjw-lisbon/</guid><description>At the DevOps World | Jenkins World 2019 Conference in Lisbon, I gave a talk titled 1 year with Jenkins X.
In this talk, I shared our experience using Jenkins X at Dailymotion for more than 1 year: how we went from the &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; to the &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo; with the &amp;ldquo;most innovative Jenkins X implementation&amp;rdquo;.
I explained how we adopted Jenkins X and its new practices – both on the organizational and technical side.</description></item><item><title>Interview with Digital Anarchist</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-12-interview-dwjw-lisbon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-12-interview-dwjw-lisbon/</guid><description>At the DevOps World | Jenkins World 2019 Conference in Lisbon, I was interviewed by Alan Shimel from Digital Anarchist.
We talked about:
Dailymotion Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s ad-tech platform Technologies we use at Dailymotion: Cloud, Kubernetes, Jenkins X Practices we use at Dailymotion: Gitops Microservices and monoliths Why people go to conferences?</description></item><item><title>Our journey from Jenkins to Jenkins X</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-06-openrday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-06-openrday/</guid><description>At the Open R&amp;amp;Day 2019 Conference in Paris, I gave a talk titled Our journey from Jenkins to Jenkins X.
In this talk, I first introduced Jenkins X, and then went through some of the benefits we gained by switching Dailymotion ad-tech platform&amp;rsquo;s CI/CD pipelines to Jenkins X: Preview Environments, easy promotion, Gitops, &amp;hellip;
I also explained how we adopted Jenkins X and did the migration, and finished with our open-source contributions as part of this migration.</description></item></channel></rss>