<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CI/CD on Vincent Behar</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/tags/ci/cd/</link><description>Recent content in CI/CD on Vincent Behar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vincent.behar.name/tags/ci/cd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Jenkins X is Integrating Observability from the Inside, and the Benefits for its Users</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-06-cdcon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-06-cdcon/</guid><description>At the cdCon conference, in june 2021, I gave a talk titled How Jenkins X is Integrating Observability from the Inside, and the Benefits for its Users.
In this talk, I explained what observability means for a Continuous Delivery platform such as Jenkins X, and why it&amp;rsquo;s important.
I went through how Jenkins X v3 is integrating observability from the inside, using standards such as OpenTelemetry, and packaging a full observability stack using Grafana - with Loki, Promtail, Tempo, and Prometheus.</description></item><item><title>Using Grafana to visualize Continuous Delivery Indicators in the open source Jenkins X cloud native CI/CD project</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-06-grafanacon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-06-grafanacon/</guid><description>At the GrafanaCONline 2021 Conference, I gave a talk titled Using Grafana to visualize Continuous Delivery Indicators in the open source Jenkins X cloud native CI/CD project - yes, I&amp;rsquo;m competing for the longest conference talk title!
In this talk, I shared how we are using Grafana in Jenkins X for everything observability-related, and more specifically to visualize Continuous Delivery Indicators:
why Grafana how Grafana is setup in a Kubernetes cluster how the CD indicators application is exposing its dashboards and datasource for Grafana to consume You can watch the talk on the Grafana website.</description></item><item><title>Collecting and visualizing Continuous Delivery Indicators</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-02-fosdem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-02-fosdem/</guid><description>At the Fosdem 2021 Conference, I gave a talk titled Collecting and visualizing Continuous Delivery Indicators in a Kubernetes-based CI/CD platform, using Jenkins X, Lighthouse, Tekton, PostgreSQL and Grafana in the CI/CD devroom.
In this talk, I shared our experience at Dailymotion on:
defining CD Indicators collecting them from a Kubernetes-based CI/CD platform storing them in PostgreSQL visualizing them using Grafana You can watch the talk on video.fosdem.org or directly here:</description></item><item><title>Dailymotion's Continuous Delivery Story</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-10-cdcon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-10-cdcon/</guid><description>At the cdCon conference, in october 2020, I gave a talk titled Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s Continuous Delivery Story.
In this talk, I explained Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s initial CI/CD-related issues back in 2018, and how we solved them:
using practices from the Accelerate book using Jenkins X - a CD platform which implements the practices from the Accelerate book Register for #cdCON 2020 Virtual Oct. 7 &amp;amp; 8. @vbehar will share Dailymotion&amp;#39;s Continuous Delivery story with @jenkinsci, @jenkinsxio &amp;amp; @tektoncd.</description></item><item><title>Jenkins X Pipelines Visualizer Demo</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-09-jx-office-hours/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-09-jx-office-hours/</guid><description>At the Jenkins X Office Hours, in september 2020, I did a demo of the new UI for Jenkins X Pipelines that we wrote at Dailymotion, and then shared as open-source with the Jenkins X community.
You can read more about it in the following Jenkins X blog post: New UI to visualize your pipelines and logs - or check out the github repository.
Update: there was a more recent blog post on New features in the pipelines visualizer UI.</description></item><item><title>Dailymotion's Continuous Delivery story with Jenkins, Jenkins X, and Tekton</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-03-article-cd-foundation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-03-article-cd-foundation/</guid><description>I wrote a blog post on the Continuous Delivery Foundation website, titled Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s Continuous Delivery story with Jenkins, Jenkins X, and Tekton.
You can read the full blog post.</description></item><item><title>Dailymotion's experience running CI/CD pipelines on Kubernetes with Jenkins X</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-03-meetup-eurodog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-03-meetup-eurodog/</guid><description>At the European DevOps Group (EuroDOG) Paris (virtual) meetup in March 2020, I gave a talk titled Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s experience running CI/CD pipelines on Kubernetes with Jenkins X.</description></item><item><title>One year with Jenkins X</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-03-article-one-year-with-jenkins-x/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-03-article-one-year-with-jenkins-x/</guid><description>One year after the initial blog post From Jenkins to Jenkins X published on Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s Medium publication, I wrote a follow-up titled One year with Jenkins X.
In this blog post I detail the technical challenges we had to overcome, and the benefits we got from using Jenkins X at Dailymotion.
The content of this blog post was also presented at the DevOps World | Jenkins World 2019 Conference in Lisbon, in my talk 1 year with Jenkins X.</description></item><item><title>Jenkins X Pipelines Internals</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-02-articles-jenkins-x-pipelines-internals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-02-articles-jenkins-x-pipelines-internals/</guid><description>While migrating pipelines from the Jenkins Declarative Syntax to the new Jenkins X YAML Syntax - built on top of Tekton - I learned a lot about the internals of the Jenkins X Pipelines, and wrote a series of blog posts to share what I learned:
The first part is a walk-through of a GitHub WebHook event coming to the cluster until it results in a running Tekton Pipeline. It explains how Prow understands the webhook event, &amp;ldquo;kind of&amp;rdquo; forwards it to Jenkins X, which retrieves the right pipeline to execute and translate it into a format that Tekton can understand.</description></item><item><title>1 year with Jenkins X</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-12-dwjw-lisbon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-12-dwjw-lisbon/</guid><description>At the DevOps World | Jenkins World 2019 Conference in Lisbon, I gave a talk titled 1 year with Jenkins X.
In this talk, I shared our experience using Jenkins X at Dailymotion for more than 1 year: how we went from the &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; to the &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo; with the &amp;ldquo;most innovative Jenkins X implementation&amp;rdquo;.
I explained how we adopted Jenkins X and its new practices – both on the organizational and technical side.</description></item><item><title>CI/CD on Kubernetes with Jenkins X</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-11-scaleup360/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-11-scaleup360/</guid><description>At the ScaleUp 360° Better Software digital event in november 2019, I gave a talk titled CI/CD on Kubernetes with Jenkins X.
In this talk, I explained how to do CI/CD on Kubernetes, and went through our experience using Jenkins X on GKE at Dailymotion:
What is Jenkins X Why and how we adopted Jenkins X at Dailymotion – and the benefits How we went from the &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; to the &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo;, and ended with the &amp;ldquo;2019 Most Innovative Jenkins X Implementation&amp;rdquo;: our custom implementation, and the integration of some open-source projects like Osiris (for auto-scaling to zero), sops (for secrets encryption) or Helmfile (to define our staging/production environments and handle deployments)</description></item><item><title>Quand la pub de Dailymotion bascule sur Jenkins X</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-10-interview-lmi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-10-interview-lmi/</guid><description>I gave an interview to Le Monde Informatique, a french IT news website, in october 2019, about Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s adoption of Jenkins X.
More specifically, about Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s ad-tech platform move to Google Cloud Platform and to Kubernetes, and its adoption of Jenkins X to run its CI/CD pipelines.
We talked about our custom implementation of Jenkins X, and open-source contributions. And of course the benefits of the migration.
Read the full interview - in french.</description></item><item><title>Our journey from Jenkins to Jenkins X</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-06-openrday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-06-openrday/</guid><description>At the Open R&amp;amp;Day 2019 Conference in Paris, I gave a talk titled Our journey from Jenkins to Jenkins X.
In this talk, I first introduced Jenkins X, and then went through some of the benefits we gained by switching Dailymotion ad-tech platform&amp;rsquo;s CI/CD pipelines to Jenkins X: Preview Environments, easy promotion, Gitops, &amp;hellip;
I also explained how we adopted Jenkins X and did the migration, and finished with our open-source contributions as part of this migration.</description></item><item><title>Our experience running Jenkins X in production</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-04-cdconference/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-04-cdconference/</guid><description>At the Continuous Delivery in a Cloud Native World virtual summit, in april 2019, I gave a talk titled Our experience running Jenkins X in production.
In this talk, I explained Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s reasons for selecting Jenkins X to run the ad-tech platform CI/CD pipelines, and shared our experience using it in production:
how we keep our Preview Environments under control using Osiris to scale them down to 0 when they are not used how we promote our releases to staging/production on different Kubernetes clusters using Helmfile – and the benefits of it.</description></item><item><title>Using and abusing Jenkins X Preview Environments</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-03-meetup-paris-cd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-03-meetup-paris-cd/</guid><description>At the Continuous Delivery Paris meetup, at the march 2019 session, I gave a talk titled Using and abusing Jenkins X Preview Environments.
In this talk, I focused on Jenkins X Preview Environments, and how we are using - and abusing - them at Dailymotion, to build and test our ad-tech platform:
what is a preview environment, how it works and its lifecycle how we are testing &amp;ldquo;managed services&amp;rdquo; using preview Environments how we are customizing the environments using Helm how we are managing the environments and avoiding too many idle resources with Osiris Using Jenkins X at @dailymotion talk by @vbehar #ci #cd pic.</description></item><item><title>Migrating our CI/CD pipelines to Kubernetes with Jenkins X</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-02-meetup-cncf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-02-meetup-cncf/</guid><description>At the Cloud Native Computing Paris meetup, at the february 2019 session, I gave a talk titled Migrating our CI/CD pipelines to Kubernetes with Jenkins X.
In this talk, I shared our experience migrating our Dailymotion ad-tech platform&amp;rsquo;s CI/CD pipeline from Jenkins to Jenkins X on Kubernetes:
Why we chose Jenkins X What are the impacts How we did this migration, in term of processes, people, practices and tools Some of the issues we had, and how we solved them And of course the next steps!</description></item><item><title>Zero cost preview environments on Kubernetes with Jenkins X and Osiris</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-02-article-osiris/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-02-article-osiris/</guid><description>In february 2019, I wrote a blog post on Medium titled Zero cost preview environments on Kubernetes with Jenkins X and Osiris, explaining how to improve Jenkins X Preview Environments using Osiris, to automatically scale down to 0 the idle environments.
You can read the full blog post on Medium.</description></item><item><title>Dailymotion's journey from Jenkins to Jenkins X</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-01-article-from-jenkins-to-jenkins-x/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-01-article-from-jenkins-to-jenkins-x/</guid><description>At the beginning of 2019, I wrote a blog post on Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s Medium publication titled Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s journey from Jenkins to Jenkins X:
it got more than 20k views in 1 year, it was re-published on CloudBees blog, it was translated in chinese by Wang Donghui, and published on InfoQ. You can read the full blog post on Medium.
Dailymotion&amp;#39;s journey from Jenkins to Jenkins X, the issues they had, and how they solved them: https://t.</description></item><item><title>Continuous Deployment with Jenkins and Rundeck</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2011-03-meetup-paris-devops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2011-03-meetup-paris-devops/</guid><description>At the Paris DevOps meetup, at the march 2011 session, I gave a talk titled Continuous Deployment with Jenkins and Rundeck with my colleague Bruno.
Bruno presented Rundeck first, and how it can be used to automate operations.
And then I explained how we used it at RTL, to build a Continuous Deployment pipeline using Jenkins and Nexus:
for our staging environment, we enabled a continuous deployment workflow - which we called &amp;ldquo;0-click deployment&amp;rdquo; for our production environment, we enabled a continuous delivery workflow - which we called &amp;ldquo;1-click deployment&amp;rdquo; Read the full meetup report - in french.</description></item></channel></rss>