<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Interview on Vincent Behar</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/tags/interview/</link><description>Recent content in Interview on Vincent Behar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vincent.behar.name/tags/interview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Examining OpenTelemetry with Vincent Behar of Ubisoft</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-10-interview-o11ycast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-10-interview-o11ycast/</guid><description>I was interviewed by Charity Majors and Liz Fong-Jones from the Observability Podcast (o11ycast).
We talked about OpenTelemetry, Continuous Delivery, and how we&amp;rsquo;ve joined the 2 together in Jenkins X.
In episode 44 of @o11ycast, @lizthegrey and @mipsytipsy speak with @vbehar of @Ubisoft. Together they pull back the curtain on @opentelemetry, as well as Vincent&amp;#39;s continuous journey to better understand the developer experience. → https://t.co/EisUIiWvMH pic.twitter.com/h0Y4yhcXpb
&amp;mdash; Heavybit (@heavybit) October 8, 2021</description></item><item><title>How we are using and contributing to Jenkins X at Dailymotion</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-05-interview-cdf-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2021-05-interview-cdf-podcast/</guid><description>I was interviewed by Jacqueline Salinas from the Continuous Delivery Foundation podcast: The Pipeline: All Things CD &amp;amp; DevOps.
We talked about how we are using and contributing to Jenkins X at Dailymotion:
our story with Jenkins X our contributions - the web UI &amp;amp; the observability stack - and why we contribute Fresh content available! Check out the latest ep. of The Pipeline: All Things CD &amp;amp; DevOps podcast.</description></item><item><title>Interview on the DevOps Radio Podcast</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-07-interview-devops-radio-podcast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2020-07-interview-devops-radio-podcast/</guid><description>At the DevOps World | Jenkins World 2019 Conference in Lisbon, I was interviewed by Brian Dawson from the DevOps Radio podcast.
We talked about:
me Dailymotion Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s ad-tech platform Continuous Delivery Jenkins X</description></item><item><title>Interview with Digital Anarchist</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-12-interview-dwjw-lisbon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-12-interview-dwjw-lisbon/</guid><description>At the DevOps World | Jenkins World 2019 Conference in Lisbon, I was interviewed by Alan Shimel from Digital Anarchist.
We talked about:
Dailymotion Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s ad-tech platform Technologies we use at Dailymotion: Cloud, Kubernetes, Jenkins X Practices we use at Dailymotion: Gitops Microservices and monoliths Why people go to conferences?</description></item><item><title>Quand la pub de Dailymotion bascule sur Jenkins X</title><link>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-10-interview-lmi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vincent.behar.name/publications/2019-10-interview-lmi/</guid><description>I gave an interview to Le Monde Informatique, a french IT news website, in october 2019, about Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s adoption of Jenkins X.
More specifically, about Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s ad-tech platform move to Google Cloud Platform and to Kubernetes, and its adoption of Jenkins X to run its CI/CD pipelines.
We talked about our custom implementation of Jenkins X, and open-source contributions. And of course the benefits of the migration.
Read the full interview - in french.</description></item></channel></rss>